#### **WILLIAM MICHAEL RANKIN**

13332 S Cedar Park Dr Herriman, UT 84096 (801) 879-0200 william.rankin01@gmail.com

# **ABOUT ME:**

I am a full-stack web developer and software engineer in process of completing the University of Utah Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp. I have twelve years of experience as a laboratory chemist, and I am looking to change direction in my career. My experience in chemistry and in pharmaceutical R&D and manufacturing has given me practical skills that will transition to my new career in web and software development.

### These skills include:

- Detail-oriented problem solving, troubleshooting.
- Processing large data sets and reviewing others work on large data sets.
- Working and communicating with a team to complete large projects on a tight timeline.
- Working independently to complete small portions of a large collaborative project.

## SKILLS:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery

- Express.js
- React.js
- Node.js
- MongoDB

- MySQL
- Git
- APIs

### **EDUCATION:**

University of Utah Coding Bootcamp April 2024

- Gained skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, jQuery, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, and Git.
- Worked together in teams to complete class projects.

Bachelor of Science, Chemistry

August 2014

Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah

- Completed courses in general, organic, physical, analytical, inorganic, and biochemistry.
- Completed lab courses in general, organic, physical, inorganic, and analytical chemistry.

## **EXPERIENCE:**

Product Development Scientist 09/2019-Present

Teva Pharmaceuticals, Salt Lake City, Utah

- Operated instruments and analyzed large data sets to detect low level compounds in pharmaceutical products.
- Authored methods and protocols for analytical testing.
- Worked independently and with a team to accomplish goals within deadlines.
- Authored and review reports that are submitted to the FDA for pharmaceutical filing.

New Product Development Analyst 12/2017–09/2019

Reckitt Benckiser, Salt Lake City, Utah

- Coordinated with quality control, engineering, production, R&D, and planning teams to develop and produce new products in the factory.
- Authored and revised protocols and SOPs for laboratory procedures using Change Control
- Lead and authored OOS investigations.
- Worked with outsource laboratories to complete testing.
- Trained analysts on new methods

On-going Stability Analyst 09/2016–12/2017

Reckitt Benckiser, Salt Lake City, Utah

- Performed stability and commercial testing for VMS and OTC products in a GMP/GLP environment.
- Built and maintained instrument methods in instrument analysis software.
- Maintained instruments and associated software, including repairs, qualification, validation, and general troubleshooting for the laboratory.

Research Assistant 08/2014–06/2016 University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah

Research Assistant 04/2011–08/2014 Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah

- Developed and documented new synthetic methods for nanoparticles.
- Eight-time recipient of Undergraduate Research Awards
- Presented research in ACS meetings and local conferences.
- Published research J. Nanosci. Nanotech. 2015, 15, 3809-3815.